<resources>
    <string name="app_name">BSC eRoots\'21</string>
    <string name="enter_email">Please Enter email:</string>
    <string name="fp"><u>Forgot Password</u>?</string>

    <string name="bscInfo"> Boston Scientific was formed June 29, 1979, in Watertown, Massachusetts, as a holding company for a medical products company called Medi-Tech, and to position the company for growth in interventional medicine.[6] Medi-Tech was the brainchild of Itzak Bentov, a Czech-born emigre to Palestine and then to the United States, who worked at the Arthur D. Little think tank in Cambridge MA, and ran a contract research company from his rented house in Belmont MA, a venture he founded in 1965 with a business friend, Dan Singer. In 1967 he was asked by Beth Israel radiologists to design a steerable, remotely controlled catheter; a series of engineering designs, polymer improvements and prototypes led to the release of a new steerable angiography catheter in 1969. That year John Abele joined the small company with an option to buy, and a year later he exercised his option with Cooper Labs as business partner, and the operation was moved out of Bentovs basement to Watertown. After a decade of steady growth, by chance Abele met Pete Nicholas in their neighborhood in Concord, MA. Their partnership hinged on Nicholas goal to build business enterprises and Abeles predilection for the vision and potential in noninvasive surgical instrumentation; they gathered backers in the Boston banking community to buy out the Cooper Labs interest and form the new corporation. Less than a year later Kimray Medical Associates (later Mansfield Scientific) was acquired, adding vena cava filters and cardiac output computers to the product line. By 1982 a renovated mill building in Watertown was transformed into a manufacturing plant. Acquisitions continued, with Endo-Tech (Microvasive: gastrointestinal and pulmonary) in 1981 and then Van-Tec (urology) in 1988, and an international presence was expanded. Boston Scientific was formed June 29, 1979, in Watertown, Massachusetts, as a holding company for a medical products company called Medi-Tech, and to position the company for growth in interventional medicine.[6] Medi-Tech was the brainchild of Itzak Bentov, a Czech-born emigre to Palestine and then to the United States, who worked at the Arthur D. Little think tank in Cambridge MA, and ran a contract research company from his rented house in Belmont MA, a venture he founded in 1965 with a business friend, Dan Singer. In 1967 he was asked by Beth Israel radiologists to design a steerable, remotely controlled catheter; a series of engineering designs, polymer improvements and prototypes led to the release of a new steerable angiography catheter in 1969. That year John Abele joined the small company with an option to buy, and a year later he exercised his option with Cooper Labs as business partner, and the operation was moved out of Bentovs basement to Watertown. After a decade of steady growth, by chance Abele met Pete Nicholas in their neighborhood in Concord, MA. Their partnership hinged on Nicholas goal to build business enterprises and Abeles predilection for the vision and potential in noninvasive surgical instrumentation; they gathered backers in the Boston banking community to buy out the Cooper Labs interest and form the new corporation. Less than a year later Kimray Medical Associates (later Mansfield Scientific) was acquired, adding vena cava filters and cardiac output computers to the product line. By 1982 a renovated mill building in Watertown was transformed into a manufacturing plant. Acquisitions continued, with Endo-Tech (Microvasive: gastrointestinal and pulmonary) in 1981 and then Van-Tec (urology) in 1988, and an international presence was expanded. </string>

</resources>